Diarmuid Brady

Email: diarmuid.b.8612@gmail.com Phone: (087) 3367887

Website: https://nearmo.github.io/personal-website/

Personal Profile

Strong problem solving skills with a keen interest in areas relating to maths, technology, self development and philosophy. In my spare time I enjoy taking on a new project or completing a course on Datacamp or Kaggle and learning new skills or reading a book about a new concept or idea. Passive interest in website creation. I am an active participant and member of the DCU Rock Climbing Club and Committee where we organise trips, events and the day to day running of the club, such as weekly training.

Languages: Python, MySQL and R. Working knowledge of HTML and CSS.

Tech Stack: Experience with Git, MySQL Workbench, RStudio, Pandas, Mathplotlib, Seaborn, Sklearn, OpenRefine,

Excel, Flask.

Education

Dublin City University B.Sc in Data Science

2019 - Present

Currently studying modules including Programming, Databases and Data Warehousing, Data Mining, Data Processing and Visualisation, Calculus and Statistics.

First Year: Placed third in my year with an average of 85%.

Second Year Data Mining Classification Project:

I worked on the Titanic Survivors dataset. I analysed the dataset then I coded a Decision Tree Classification algorithm to predict whether a passenger survived or not. I evaluated the results by assessing the predictive accuracy of the model. **Tech Used:** Python, Pandas, Numpy, Mathplotlib, Seaborn, Sklearn

Second Year Data Cleaning Project:

Tasked with cleaning, combining and processing a series of datasets of different file types which counted the footfall of people every hour in several locations over a number of years in Dublin, into one unified dataset.

Tech Used: Python, Pandas, Excel, Colab Notebooks, Google Maps

Cnoc Mhuire Secondary School, Granard, Co. Longford Leaving Certificate:

2013-2019 544 Points

Work Experience

Programming Tutor at Dublin City University

September 2020 - Present

- I tutor modules in Computer Programming (Python), Databases (MySQL) and Web Design (HTML and CSS) for both first and second year students.
- I assist students in working through challenges by using a systematic approach of problem solving.
- I attempt to instill quality programming practices by discussing different coding conventions and I encourage students to strive for simplicity in their programs as this often leads to greatest efficiency, readability and usability.

General Operative at Floods Precast

June 2020 - September 2020

- Preparing beds with steel, to pour concrete into.
- Tasked with operating large machinery eg. a gantry for moving necessary materials.
- Disassemble beds for removing concrete slabs for transport.

Sales Assistant at Rapture Jack & Jones

Dec 2019 - Jan 2020

- In charge of taking in and packing out large deliveries.
- Maintaining shop and clothing presentations standards
- Assisting customers in the process and purchasing items and serving customers at checkout

Grinds teacher Sept 2019 – Present

• Providing Leaving & Junior Cert grinds to students in the subjects Maths, Technical Graphics.

- Teaching students the necessary skills to excel in their exams as well as helping them to understand the underlying concepts of the subject.
- Advertising grinds using ad campaigns through Facebook and Instagram page: grinds jc.lc

Camp Leader in Lus Na Gréine Family Resource Centre

June 2019 - July 2019

• Tasked with supervising over 30 children at a time, teaching cooking skills, organising problem solving games and taking charge of other fun learning activities.

General Operative at Dunphy's SuperValu

Jan 2017 - Aug 2018

- In charge of stacking shelves with fresh produce in the Fruit & Veg and Dairy aisles.
- Tasked with providing management with reports and carrying out general cleaning and maintenance cleaning.
- Trusted with opening the shop and locking up at closing hours.

General Operative at Moulding Technology (TY Experience)

Sept 2019 - Oct 2019

- Tasked with operating Injection Moulding Machinery.
- In charge of stripping down and cleaning mould after machine use in order to maintain machine integrity

Awards and Achievements

- Placed 3rd in my course in my first year studying Data Science.
- Recipient of Cnoc Mhuire award for excellence in leaving cert (544 points).
- Attained full attendance in Leaving Cert year 2018-2019 showcasing excellent punctuality.
- Recipient of student mentor award in leaving cert year for mentoring a small group of 1st year students and helping them settle into life at secondary school.
- Participated in the All-Ireland Junior Maths Competition.
- Longford Minor Division 2 Championship Final Winner with Northern Gaels 2017.

Interests and Hobbies

- Strong interest in Hackathons Attended Hacktoberfest in DCU. Looking to improve coding skills and attend further hackathons in the future.
- Member of Redbrick Society We have discussed areas such as AWS and machine learning and have had guest speakers from different companies talking about the tech stack they use and how they handle data.
- Actively involved in the Rock Climbing Club in DCU.
- Hobbies include calisthenics, rock climbing, gymnastics as well as reading books and listening to podcasts on topics such as self development, philosophy and psychology.